(Thank You, Doctor)
(شكرا يا دكتور)
(Adapted from Sheng Li's novel "ICU 48 Hours")
(مقتبس من رواية شنغ لي "ICU 48 Hours")
(Episode 26)
(الحلقة 26)
I got it now.
حصلت عليها الان.
He didn't want to spend money.
لم يكن يريد أن ينفق المال.
That's why he didn't want the surgery.
لهذا السبب لم يكن يريد الجراحة.
Yes.
نعم.
We have to compensate the lady.
علينا تعويض السيدة.
We have to pay for my tuition too.
علينا أن ندفع مصاريف دراستي أيضًا.
He has no choice.
ليس لديه خيار.
However,
لكن،
he can't risk his life at this moment.
لا يمكنه المخاطرة بحياته في هذه اللحظة.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I'll convince my dad.
سأقنع والدي.
We have to do this surgery.
علينا إجراء هذه الجراحة.
Thank you, doctor.
شكرا لك دكتور.
I've always thought...
لطالما اعتقدت ...
that money and life can't be treated equally.
لا يمكن التعامل مع هذا المال والحياة على قدم المساواة.
Now only I know...
الآن فقط أعرف ...
that this is the hardest choice...
أن هذا هو الخيار الأصعب ...
for many families.
للعديد من العائلات.
I've thought of a way to help her.
لقد فكرت في طريقة لمساعدتها.
Let's go find Dr. Lu.
دعنا نذهب للعثور على الدكتور لو.
Dad, have another sip.
أبي ، رشفة أخرى.
No.
رقم.
Yun Yun.
يون يون.
Put the water aside.
ضع الماء جانبًا.
I have something to tell you.
لدي شيء لأخبرك به.
Leave it there.
اتركه هناك.
Yun Yun.
يون يون.
Listen to me.
استمع لي.
Let's not do this surgery.
دعونا لا نجري هذه الجراحة.
Dad.
أب.
Let me finish.
دعني انتهي.
As you know,
وانت عارف،
I've been having this chest pain...
لقد كنت أعاني من هذا الألم في الصدر ...
for many years.
لعدة سنوات.
It has been like this since you were little.
لقد كان مثل هذا منذ أن كنت صغيرا.
Until now,
حتى الآن،
nothing happened, right?
لم يحدث شيء ، صحيح؟
The hospital doesn't want to take responsibility.
لا تريد المستشفى تحمل المسؤولية.
That's why they make it sound very serious.
لهذا السبب يجعلون الأمر يبدو جادًا جدًا.
They're afraid that if...
إنهم يخشون أنه إذا ...
If something happens,
إذا حدث شيء ما ،
they can get away with it.
يمكنهم الإفلات من العقاب.
Trust me.
صدقني.
I know how healthy I am.
أعرف كم أنا بصحة جيدة.
I'll be fine.
سأكون بخير.
Tomorrow,
الغد،
we'll ask to be discharged.
سنطلب الخروج من المستشفى.
As for me,
بالنسبة لي،
I'll just focus on driving...
سأركز فقط على القيادة ...
to earn money.
لكسب المال.
You just focus on your study and go to college.
أنت فقط تركز على دراستك وتذهب إلى الكلية.
Dad.
أب.
Stop lying to yourself.
توقف عن الكذب على نفسك.
I've looked up your illness online.
لقد بحثت عن مرضك على الإنترنت.
The doctor is right.
الطبيب على حق.
You have to put the stent in.
عليك أن تضع الدعامة.
Dad.
أب.
I know you don't want to spend this money,
أعلم أنك لا تريد إنفاق هذا المال ،
but this is to save your life.
لكن هذا لإنقاذ حياتك.
What's wrong with you?
ما مشكلتك؟
Do you believe everything you read online?
هل تصدق كل ما تقرأه على الإنترنت؟
There are a lot of scams online.
هناك الكثير من الحيل على الإنترنت.
You believe everything online but not your dad.
أنت تصدق كل شيء عبر الإنترنت ولكن ليس والدك.
Look at our family situation.
انظر إلى وضع عائلتنا.
You know that.
هل تعلم أن.
Dad hit someone.
ضرب أبي شخص ما.
We have to compensate her.
علينا تعويضها.
We can't go against our conscience.
لا يمكننا أن نتعارض مع ضميرنا.
No, you still have to go to college.
لا ، لا يزال عليك الذهاب إلى الكلية.
I can't stay in the hospital and waste money.
لا أستطيع البقاء في المستشفى وأهدر المال.
Dad.
أب.
You've raised me for 18 years.
لقد ربيتني لمدة 18 عامًا.
It's my turn to take care of you now.
حان دوري للاعتناء بك الآن.
Silly child.
طفل سخيف.
You're my good daughter.
أنت ابنتي الطيبة.
If you don't take care of me when I'm old, who will?
إذا كنت لا تعتني بي عندما أكون كبيرًا في السن ، فمن سيفعل ذلك؟
Starting tomorrow, I'll take care of you.
ابتداءً من الغد ، سأعتني بك.
You just treat your illness in the hospital...
أنت فقط تعالج مرضك في المستشفى ...
and undergo surgery.
ويخضع لعملية جراحية.
What...
ماذا او ما...
What are you trying to do?
ماذا تحاول أن تفعل؟
I...
أنا...
I'll look for a part-time job and study part-time.
سأبحث عن وظيفة بدوام جزئي وأدرس بدوام جزئي.
What nonsense are you talking about?
ما هذا الهراء الذي تتحدث عنه؟
I'm not talking nonsense.
أنا لا أتحدث عن هذا الهراء.
You said it yourself.
قلت ذلك بنفسك.
Given the situation of our family,
بالنظر إلى حالة عائلتنا ،
even if you drive for 48 hours a day,
حتى لو كنت تقود لمدة 48 ساعة في اليوم ،
you won't make enough money to pay them.
لن تكسب ما يكفي من المال لدفعها.
If I look for a part-time job, I can also share your burden.
إذا كنت أبحث عن وظيفة بدوام جزئي ، يمكنني أيضًا مشاركة عبءك.
I don't need you to help me with family matters.
لا أحتاج منك أن تساعدني في شؤون الأسرة.
Your task now is to get into college and study hard.
مهمتك الآن هي الالتحاق بالجامعة والدراسة الجادة.
I know...
أنا أعرف...
you want to become a lawyer since you were young.
تريد أن تصبح محاميًا منذ أن كنت صغيرًا.
All these years,
كل هذه السنوات،
you've suffered so much.
لقد عانيت كثيرا.
It wasn't easy for you to get into law school.
لم يكن من السهل عليك الالتحاق بكلية الحقوق.
No, you can't...
لا ، لا يمكنك ...
You have to go to school.
لديك للذهاب إلى المدرسة.
You can't be distracted from studying.
لا يمكنك أن تشتت انتباهك عن الدراسة.
Dad.
أب.
It's okay.
حسنا.
I'm still young.
ما زلت صغيرا.
I have plenty of energy.
لدي الكثير من الطاقة.
I can work and study at the same time.
يمكنني العمل والدراسة في نفس الوقت.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
You just treat your illness in the hospital...
أنت فقط تعالج مرضك في المستشفى ...
and undergo surgery.
ويخضع لعملية جراحية.
From now on,
من الان فصاعدا،
I'll take care of our family matters.
سأعتني بشؤون عائلتنا.
How are you going to do that?
كيف أنت ذاهب للقيام بذلك؟
You're driving me crazy.
انت تقودني للجنون.
I'm still alive.
ما زلت حيا.
I don't need you to worry about family matters.
لا داعي للقلق بشأن شؤون الأسرة.
Dad.
أب.
I don't have a mom anymore.
ليس لدي أم بعد الآن.
I can't lose you as well.
لا أستطيع أن أفقدك أيضًا.
I'm begging you, all right?
أتوسل إليك ، حسنًا؟
Listen to me this time.
استمع إلي هذه المرة.
My dear daughter.
ابنتي العزيزة.
Yun Yun.
يون يون.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I'm too ashamed to face your mom when I get down there.
أشعر بالخجل من مواجهة والدتك عندما أنزل هناك.
Dad.
أب.
What did I do to deserve this?
ماذا فعلت لاستحق ذلك؟
Sir.
سيد.
You have a heart condition.
لديك مرض في القلب.
You shouldn't get so worked up.
لا يجب أن تنشغل بهذه الطريقة.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Dad, stop crying.
أبي ، توقف عن البكاء.
I'm sorry about that.
أنا آسف لذلك.
We have good news.
لدينا أخبار جيدة.
Good news?
أخبار جيدة؟
Here's the thing.
هنا الحاجة.
There was a patient and his family...
كان هناك مريض وعائلته ...
worked together with our hospital...
عملت مع مستشفانا ...
to establish a medical fund...
لتأسيس صندوق طبي ...
dedicated to helping...
مكرسة لمساعدة ...
severely ill patients with financial trouble.
المرضى الذين يعانون من مرض شديد يعانون من مشاكل مالية.
Just now, we also talked to Dr. Lu...
الآن ، تحدثنا أيضًا إلى الدكتور لو ...
and the person in charge of the fund...
والشخص المسؤول عن الصندوق ...
about the situation of your family.
حول وضع عائلتك.
The other party has agreed.
وافق الطرف الآخر.
They'll pay 90 percent of your medical expenses...
سيدفعون 90 بالمائة من نفقاتك الطبية ...
in addition to health insurance.
بالإضافة إلى التأمين الصحي.
That includes hospitalization fees, medical expenses,
ويشمل ذلك رسوم العلاج في المستشفى ، والنفقات الطبية ،
surgery costs, and the cost of a stent.
تكاليف الجراحة وتكلفة الدعامة.
You just need to pay 10 percent of it.
ما عليك سوى دفع 10 بالمائة منه.
That's great.
ذلك رائع.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Don't thank us.
لا تشكرنا.
You should thank the medical foundation.
يجب أن تشكر المؤسسة الطبية.
They'll have someone in charge to talk to you later.
سيكون لديهم شخص مسؤول للتحدث معك لاحقًا.
So?
لذا؟
Have you thought about the surgery?
هل فكرت في الجراحة؟
I'll do it.
سأفعل ذلك.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Hello.
مرحبًا.
Hello? You're still up?
مرحبًا؟  هل ما زلت مستيقظًا؟
Yes. Anything?
نعم.  اى شى؟
I just remembered that patient named Fang Jing Xuan.
لقد تذكرت للتو ذلك المريض المسمى فانغ جينغ شوان.
The ballet dancer.
راقصة الباليه.
Has she agreed to the surgery?
هل وافقت على الجراحة؟
I'm still working on it.
أنا لا تزال تعمل على ذلك.
It's okay.
حسنا.
We'll cross the bridge when we come to it.
سنعبر الجسر عندما نصل إليه.
Don't be too anxious.
لا تكن قلقا جدا.
It's getting late.
الوقت يتأخر.
You should get some rest.
يجب عليك الحصول على بعض الراحة.
Okay, thank you.
حسنا شكرا لك.
Good night.
طاب مساؤك.
It's my turn.
انه دوري.
These are the successful cases of burr hole craniotomy...
هذه هي الحالات الناجحة لحجر القحف بفتحة ثقب ...
that I organized.
التي نظمتها.
Actually, this surgery has a very high success rate.
في الواقع ، هذه الجراحة لها نسبة نجاح عالية جدًا.
I saw your CT scan.
لقد رأيت الأشعة المقطعية الخاصة بك.
The bleeding isn't that bad.
النزيف ليس بهذا السوء.
If we remove the hematoma in time and drain the blood,
إذا قمنا بإزالة الورم الدموي في الوقت المناسب واستنزاف الدم ،
it won't affect your performance in a month.
لن يؤثر على أدائك خلال شهر.
Can I really go to the Mariinsky Theatre to dance?
هل يمكنني حقًا الذهاب إلى مسرح ماريانسكي لأرقص؟
We'll help you keep the epidural hematoma under control.
سنساعدك على إبقاء الورم الدموي فوق الجافية تحت السيطرة.
Most people usually take a few months to recover.
يستغرق معظم الناس عادةً بضعة أشهر للتعافي.
But I trust you.
لكن انا اثق بك.
You're a professional dancer.
أنت راقصة محترفة.
You're strong-willed.
أنت قوي الإرادة.
After a month, you can return to the stage.
بعد شهر يمكنك العودة إلى المسرح.
However, you have to promise me one thing.
ومع ذلك ، عليك أن تعدني بشيء واحد.
Once the show is over,
بمجرد انتهاء العرض ،
you have to come back right away to cure the illness.
عليك العودة على الفور لعلاج المرض.
Were you bribed by my parents?
هل رشوت من والداي؟
Did you come up with fake cases to deceive me?
هل توصلت إلى قضايا وهمية لخداعتي؟
Your family complained about me.
عائلتك اشتكت مني.
They even reported it to my chief.
حتى أنهم أبلغوا رئيس بلدي.
Do you think I'll collude with them?
هل تعتقد أنني سأتآمر معهم؟
They did it for my own good. Please don't blame them.
لقد فعلوها من أجل مصلحتي.  من فضلك لا تلومهم.
I can assure you.
يمكنني أن أؤكد لكم.
These are all real cases.
هذه كلها حالات حقيقية.
Then you'll have to write me an affidavit.
ثم عليك أن تكتب لي إفادة خطية.
Promise me that after the surgery,
أوعدني أنه بعد الجراحة ،
I'll be able to participate in the show.
سأكون قادرا على المشاركة في العرض.
All surgeries have risks.
جميع العمليات الجراحية لها مخاطر.
I can't absolutely promise success.
لا أستطيع أن أعدك بالنجاح على الإطلاق.
Besides, our hospital...
الى جانب ذلك ، مستشفانا ...
doesn't allow us to make such promises to patients.
لا تسمح لنا بتقديم مثل هذه الوعود للمرضى.
Then why should I believe you?
فلماذا أصدقك؟
Once I'm under anesthesia,
بمجرد أن أكون تحت التخدير ،
I won't know anything.
لن اعرف شيئا.
You'll operate me however you want.
ستديرني كيفما تريد.
It'll be too late for me to regret it by then.
سيكون الوقت قد فات بالنسبة لي لأن أندم عليه بحلول ذلك الوقت.
Let me put it this way.
اسمحوا لي أن أطرح السؤال بهذه الطريقة.
If I wanted to lie to you,
إذا أردت أن أكذب عليك ،
I wouldn't have exposed your parents.
لم أكن لأكشف والديك.
Back then, you're about to sign the agreement.
في ذلك الوقت ، كنت على وشك توقيع الاتفاقية.
Even though I can't promise you anything,
على الرغم من أنني لا أستطيع أن أعدك بأي شيء ،
I'll tell you anyway.
سأخبرك على أي حال.
We respect life.
نحن نحترم الحياة.
We respect patients' rights.
نحن نحترم حقوق المرضى.
We respect everyone's dream even more.
نحن نحترم حلم الجميع أكثر.
Please believe in us.
الرجاء الإيمان بنا.
Dr. Xiao.
دكتور شياو.
Xuan Xuan has signed it.
وقد وقعها Xuan Xuan.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Before this, I was too anxious.
قبل ذلك ، كنت قلقة للغاية.
I had some misunderstanding with Dr. Bai...
كان لدي بعض سوء التفاهم مع الدكتور باي ...
and I was rude to him.
وكنت وقحا معه.
How about this?
وماذا عن هذا؟
I'll apologize to him in person.
سأعتذر له شخصيا.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Yes.
نعم.
If Dr. Bai hadn't come here early in the morning...
إذا لم يأتِ الدكتور باي إلى هنا في الصباح الباكر ...
and explained to Xuan Xuan patiently,
وشرح لـ Xuan Xuan بصبر ،
Xuan Xuan wouldn't have agreed to the surgery so soon.
لم يوافق Xuan Xuan على الجراحة قريبًا.
Aren't you off today?
ألست في إجازة اليوم؟
Why did you come to the hospital?
لماذا أتيت إلى المستشفى؟
You're so professional, just like him.
أنت محترف للغاية ، مثله تمامًا.
I wonder what he's up to.
أتساءل ما الذي سيفعله.
Xiao Guang told me...
شياو غوانغ قال لي ...
that he did some research all night yesterday.
أنه أجرى بعض البحث طوال ليلة أمس.
He came here first thing in the morning.
لقد جاء إلى هنا أول شيء في الصباح.
I'm going to make my rounds.
سأقوم بجولاتي.
The surgery was a success.
ان الجراحة كانت ناجحة.
The epidural hematoma has been removed.
تمت إزالة الورم الدموي فوق الجافية.
If nothing unusual comes up,
إذا لم يظهر شيء غير عادي ،
she can be discharged in a week.
يمكن أن تخرج من المستشفى في غضون أسبوع.
Can I go...
أيمكنني الذهاب...
to the Mariinsky Theatre?
إلى مسرح ماريانسكي؟
Yes, you can. The doctor said you can.
نعم تستطيع.  قال الطبيب يمكنك.
One month before the show,
قبل شهر من العرض ،
you have to pay more attention to rest and nutrition.
عليك أن تولي المزيد من الاهتمام للراحة والتغذية.
We'll prescribe her...
سنصفها ...
some anti-seizure medicine and painkillers.
بعض الأدوية المضادة للتشنج ومسكنات الألم.
Make sure she takes them.
تأكد من أنها تأخذهم.
Once the show goes well,
بمجرد أن يسير العرض على ما يرام ،
remember to come back for the surgery.
تذكر العودة للجراحة.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Hello, Dr. Xiao.
مرحبا دكتور شياو.
I'm here to visit Fang Jing Xuan.
أنا هنا لزيارة فانغ جينغ شوان.
I heard she just had surgery.
سمعت أنها أجريت للتو عملية جراحية.
Don't worry. The surgery was a success.
لا تقلق.  ان الجراحة كانت ناجحة.
That's great.
ذلك رائع.
Can I go see her?
هل يمكنني الذهاب لرؤيتها؟
We need to ask the patient and her family first.
نحتاج أن نسأل المريضة وعائلتها أولاً.
Dr. Xiao.
دكتور شياو.
Perfect timing.
توقيت ممتاز.
Sir and ma'am.
سيدي وسيدتي.
I'm here to visit Fang Jing Xuan.
أنا هنا لزيارة فانغ جينغ شوان.
There's 5,000 yuan in here.
هناك 5000 يوان هنا.
Please accept it.
ارجوك اقبله.
Sir.
سيد.
All the money my dad earned over the years...
كل الأموال التي كسبها والدي على مر السنين ...
has been used for me to go to school.
تم استخدامه لي للذهاب إلى المدرسة.
We don't have much savings.
ليس لدينا الكثير من المدخرات.
On top of that, he has been hospitalized recently.
علاوة على ذلك ، تم إدخاله إلى المستشفى مؤخرًا.
This is all we can spare.
هذا كل ما يمكننا تجنيبه.
Please don't worry.
من فضلك لا تقلق.
We'll definitely pay you back.
سنعيد لك بالتأكيد.
We will pay off the money...
سندفع المال ...
slowly in the future.
ببطء في المستقبل.
Miss.
يغيب.
Take this money back.
خذ هذه الأموال.
We can't accept it.
لا يمكننا قبوله.
If it weren't for this car accident,
إذا لم يكن لحادث السيارة هذا ،
we wouldn't know that Xuan Xuan has a glioma in her brain.
لن نعرف أن شوان شوان لديها ورم دبقي في دماغها.
Isn't this a blessing in disguise?
أليست هذه نعمة مقنعة؟
Actually, this is Xuan Xuan's idea.
في الواقع ، هذه هي فكرة Xuan Xuan.
Before the surgery,
قبل الجراحة ،
she found out about your family's situation.
اكتشفت حالة عائلتك.
She kept telling us...
ظلت تخبرنا ...
not to look into your dad's fault anymore.
لا تنظر في خطأ والدك بعد الآن.
The money is for your tuition.
المال لرسومك الدراسية.
Thank you, sir.
شكرا لك سيدي.
Thank you, ma'am.
شكرا سيدتي.
I'll take you in to see Xuan Xuan.
سآخذك لرؤية شوان شوان.
When she wakes up,
عندما تستيقظ ،
she's worried about you and your dad.
إنها قلقة عليك وعلى والدك.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Dr. Xiao, I'll talk to you later.
دكتور شياو ، سأتحدث معك لاحقًا.
I really want to see you on stage with my own eyes.
أريد حقًا أن أراك على المسرح بأم عيني.
I believe that in a month,
أعتقد أنه في غضون شهر ،
you'll be able to stand on the stage of the Mariinsky Theatre...
ستتمكن من الوقوف على خشبة مسرح Mariinsky ...
and realize your dream.
وتحقيق حلمك.
I will.
أنا سوف.
Enough about me.
كفى عني.
What is your dream?
ما هو حلمك؟
I heard you're going to law school.
سمعت أنك ذاهب إلى كلية الحقوق.
I just started last month.
لقد بدأت للتو الشهر الماضي.
In my spare time,
في وقت فراغي،
I'll also work as an intern at a law firm.
سأعمل أيضًا كمتدرب في شركة محاماة.
Working part-time?
هل تعمل بدوام جزئي؟
Kind of.
نوعا من.
I can also lessen my dad's burden.
يمكنني أيضًا تخفيف عبء والدي.
That's amazing.
هذا مذهل.
I can't let my parents hear this.
لا يمكنني السماح لوالدي بسماع هذا.
Until now, I'm still spending their money.
حتى الآن ، ما زلت أنفق أموالهم.
That's not true.
هذا ليس صحيحا.
In the future, I'm sure you'll do better than me.
في المستقبل ، أنا متأكد من أنك ستفعل أفضل مني.
We'll both get better.
كلانا سوف يتحسن.
Hello, Dr. Xu.
مرحبا دكتور شو.
The rice is quite salty today.
الأرز مالح جدا اليوم.
You know it's salty even before you eat it.
أنت تعلم أنها مالحة حتى قبل أن تأكلها.
Tang Hua.
تانغ هوا.
Your mixed nuts look delicious.
تبدو المكسرات المشكلة الخاصة بك لذيذة.
Hello.
مرحبًا.
He's acting suspiciously.
إنه يتصرف بشكل مريب.
Who calls him?
من يناديه؟
He's just being mysterious.
إنه مجرد كونه غامض.
Go ahead and eat.
انطلق وتناول الطعام.
I'm full.
انا ممتلئ.
Where's Dr. Tang?
أين دكتور تانغ؟
Dr. Tang said you're trying to be mysterious.
قال الدكتور تانغ أنك تحاول أن تكون غامضًا.
She left.
لقد غادرت.
Your face changes really fast.
يتغير وجهك بسرعة كبيرة.
You're lucky that he didn't give you a sour look.
أنت محظوظ لأنه لم يعطيك نظرة حزينة.
- Hua'er, you're back. - Mom.
- هواير ، لقد عدت.  - أم.
I'll put the clothing disinfectant here.
سأضع مطهر الملابس هنا.
Good, you're back just in time.
جيد ، لقد عدت في الوقت المناسب.
Wash your hands and eat.
اغسل يديك وتناول الطعام.
It smells so good.
رائحتها جيدة جدا.
What delicious food did you make?
ما هو الطعام اللذيذ الذي صنعته؟
There are so many dishes.
هناك الكثير من الأطباق.
Are we expecting someone?
هل نتوقع شخص ما؟
He's already here.
إنه هنا بالفعل.
He has been busy all-day in the kitchen.
كان مشغولا طوال اليوم في المطبخ.
Who is it?
من هذا؟
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
Your mom called me.
اتصلت والدتك بي.
She said she made something delicious for me.
قالت إنها صنعت شيئًا لذيذًا بالنسبة لي.
She asked me to come and try it.
طلبت مني المجيء وتجربتها.
You have no idea.
ليس لديك فكرة.
Initially,
بدءًا،
I wanted Chen Zhi to try my cooking.
أردت أن يجرب Chen Zhi الطبخ.
But Chen Zhi came...
لكن تشين تشي جاء ...
and made all this delicious food.
وصنعت كل هذا الطعام اللذيذ.
They're all your favorites.
هم كل ما تفضله.
Someone like Chen Zhi can even cook.
يمكن لشخص مثل Chen Zhi الطهي.
I think it's not easy.
أعتقد أنه ليس من السهل.
He can even go to the bathroom himself.
يمكنه حتى الذهاب إلى الحمام بنفسه.
How can you say that?
كيف يمكنك أن تقول ذلك؟
Ignore her. Come, sit down.
تجاهلها.  تعال واجلس.
Let's eat.
لنأكل.
Have some coconut water.
تناول القليل من ماء جوز الهند.
Thank you, ma'am.
شكرا سيدتي.
Here, have some coconut water.
هنا ، تناولي بعض ماء جوز الهند.
Ma'am, have a seat. Let's eat.
سيدتي ، أجلسي.  لنأكل.
The rice is simmering.
الأرز يغلي.
I'll leave you two to talk.
سأترك لكم اثنين للحديث.
Who told you to come?
من قال لك أن تأتي؟
Why didn't you tell me when my mom called you?
لماذا لم تخبرني عندما اتصلت بك أمي؟
When your mom called me at noon,
عندما اتصلت بي والدتك ظهرا ،
we were eating in the cafeteria.
كنا نأكل في الكافتيريا.
I was going to tell you.
كنت سأخبرك.
However, after I answered the call,
ومع ذلك ، بعد أن رددت على المكالمة ،
you left.
انت غادرت.
Don't give me excuses.
لا تعطيني الأعذار.
I was in the department this afternoon.
كنت في القسم بعد ظهر اليوم.
Why didn't you tell me?
لماذا لم تخبرني
I forgot.
انا نسيت.
You forgot?
أنت نسيت؟
I think you did it on purpose.
أعتقد أنك فعلت ذلك عن قصد.
- No, I didn't... - Did what on purpose?
- لا ، لم أفعل ... - فعل ماذا عن قصد؟
Mom. Why were you eavesdropping?
أم.  لماذا كنت تتنصت؟
She's just concerned about us.
إنها مهتمة بنا فقط.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
It's nothing.
إنه لاشيء.
Ma'am.
أملك
There's so much delicious food.
هناك الكثير من الطعام اللذيذ.
I'm a little excited.
أنا متحمس قليلاً.
You made all these dishes yourself.
لقد صنعت كل هذه الأطباق بنفسك.
Why are you so excited?
لماذا انت متحمس جدا؟
Come on. Let's eat.
هيا.  لنأكل.
Tang Hua.
تانغ هوا.
Don't be mad, Tang Hua.
لا تغضب ، تانغ هوا.
I...
أنا...
- I shouldn't have... - I know what you're thinking.
- لا يجب أن أمتلك ... - أعرف ما تفكر فيه.
Do you think I'll give you a chance if you win over my mom?
هل تعتقد أنني سأعطيك فرصة إذا فزت على أمي؟
Listen. I won't.
استمع.  أنا لن.
I won't for sure.
لن أفعل ذلك بالتأكيد.
The more you please her, the more I hate you.
كلما كنت ترضيها أكثر ، أكرهك أكثر.
Do you understand?
هل تفهم؟
Tang Hua.
تانغ هوا.
Spicy hot pot.
سبايسي هوت بوت.
It's good, right?
هذا جيد ، صحيح؟
It's good.
إنه جيد.
It's spicy.
إنه حار.
Dr. Xu.
دكتور شو.
I need your help.
انا بحاجة الى مساعدتكم.
I knew it. There's no such thing as a free midnight snack.
كنت أعرف.  لا يوجد شيء اسمه وجبة خفيفة مجانية في منتصف الليل.
For the sake of this delicious food,
من أجل هذا الطعام اللذيذ ،
tell me about it.
حدثني عنها.
It's about me and Tang Hua.
إنه عني وعن تانغ هوا.
It's just as I expected.
إنه تمامًا كما توقعت.
Dr. Xu, please help me.
دكتور شو ، الرجاء مساعدتي.
If you take advantage of me, I'll take advantage of you.
إذا استفدت مني ، فسوف أستفيد منك.
Let me give you a piece of advice.
دعني أقدم لك نصيحة.
For people like you who have no talent,
لأناس مثلك ليس لديهم موهبة ،
there's only one ultimate technique.
هناك أسلوب نهائي واحد فقط.
Never give up and persevere.
لا تستسلم أبدا والمثابرة.
I can do it.
أستطيع أن أفعل ذلك.
Dr. Tang, are you waiting for a taxi?
دكتور تانغ ، هل تنتظر سيارة أجرة؟
It's hard to get a taxi at this hour.
من الصعب الحصول على سيارة أجرة في هذه الساعة.
Get in. Let's go together.
ادخل. دعنا نذهب معا.
You're shameless.
أنت وقح.
You're so persistent.
أنت مثابر جدا.
Dr. Tang.
دكتور.  تانغ.
Dr. Tang, get in.
دكتور تانغ ، ادخل.
You can't be late.
لا يمكنك أن تتأخر.
Dr. Tang.
دكتور.  تانغ.
Dr. Tang, get in the car.
دكتور تانغ ، اركب السيارة.
You're going to be late.
سوف تتأخر.
There's still a lot to do at work.
لا يزال هناك الكثير للقيام به في العمل.
Dr. Tang.
دكتور.  تانغ.
Drive faster.
محرك أسرع.
Don't worry. I promise we won't be late.
لا تقلق.  أعدك أننا لن نتأخر.
Who did you borrow the car from this time?
من اقترضت السيارة من هذا الوقت؟
I didn't borrow it.
أنا لم أستعيره.
I rented it.
لقد استأجرتها.
You're so rich.
أنت غني جدًا.
You don't go to the hospital.
لا تذهب إلى المستشفى.
Why are you loitering in front of my house?
لماذا تتسكع أمام منزلي؟
I'm not loitering.
أنا لا أتسكع.
It's on my way.
إنه في طريقي.
If I remember correctly,
إذا كنت أتذكر بشكل صحيح،
you stay in Pudong.
أنت تقيم في بودونغ.
Which route did you take?
ما الطريق الذي سلكته؟
I had some business to take care of,
كان لدي بعض الأعمال لأعتني بها ،
so I'm going the same way.
لذلك أنا ذاهب بنفس الطريقة.
How could you lie like that?
كيف يمكنك أن تكذب هكذا؟
You're getting more shameless.
أنت تزداد وقاحة.
It's true.
انها حقيقة.
You're not ashamed. Instead, you're proud of it.
أنت لا تخجل.  بدلاً من ذلك ، أنت فخور بذلك.
Don't tell anyone that you fetched me here.
لا تخبر أحدا أنك جلبتني إلى هنا.
Don't worry. I won't tell anyone.
لا تقلق.  لن أخبر أحدا.
Good morning, Dr. Xu.
صباح الخير دكتور شو.
When I was parking just now,
عندما كنت أقف سيارتي الآن ،
I saw you and Tang Hua came together.
رأيتك وتانغ هوا اجتمعت معًا.
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
I rented a car...
استأجرت سيارة ...
and waited for her downstairs.
وانتظرتها في الطابق السفلي.
She woke up late...
استيقظت متأخرة ...
and she couldn't get a taxi,
ولم تستطع ركوب سيارة أجرة ،
so we came together.
لذلك اجتمعنا.
Not bad.
ليس سيئًا.
- Isn't that great advice? - Yes.
- أليست هذه نصيحة عظيمة؟  - نعم.
She even praised me for being shameless...
حتى أنها أشادت بي لكوني وقح ...
on our way here.
في طريقنا إلى هنا.
Is that a compliment?
هل هذا مجاملة؟
Dr. Xiao.
دكتور شياو.
The patient is a male.
المريض ذكر.
He's 50 years old.
يبلغ من العمر 50 عامًا.
He has abdominal distension.
لديه انتفاخ في البطن.
He had blood in his stool this morning,
كان هناك دم في برازه هذا الصباح ،
so he suspects he has hemorrhoids.
لذلك يشتبه في إصابته بالبواسير.
I did a blood test on him.
لقد أجريت له فحص دم.
No abnormalities were found in digital rectal examination.
لم يتم العثور على أي شذوذ في فحص المستقيم الرقمي.
The possibility of intestinal tumor is not ruled out.
لا يستبعد احتمال وجود ورم معوي.
Do you mean intestinal cancer?
هل تقصد سرطان الأمعاء؟
That's impossible.
هذا مستحيل.
I pay great attention to my body maintenance.
أنا أولي اهتماما كبيرا لصيانة جسدي.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
Body maintenance is one thing.
صيانة الجسم شيء واحد.
There are actually many reasons for intestinal tumors.
هناك بالفعل أسباب عديدة لأورام الأمعاء.
In addition to the high fat and low cellulose diet,
بالإضافة إلى النظام الغذائي عالي الدهون ومنخفض السليلوز ،
there are also genetic reasons,
هناك أيضًا أسباب وراثية ،
including chronic inflammation of the intestine.
بما في ذلك التهاب الأمعاء المزمن.
They can all lead to cancer.
يمكن أن تؤدي جميعها إلى الإصابة بالسرطان.
I'll arrange a colonoscopy for you later.
سأرتب لك تنظير القولون لاحقًا.
Okay.
تمام.
Over there.
هناك.
Dr. Xiao.
دكتور شياو.
You're finally here.
أنت هنا أخيرًا.
That patient just now...
هذا المريض للتو ...
is an experienced Chinese medicine practitioner.
هو ممارس من ذوي الخبرة في الطب الصيني.
He has been nagging me all morning.
لقد كان يزعجني طوال الصباح.
He nags more than my mom.
إنه يتذمر أكثر من أمي.
What did he say?
ماذا قال؟
He said he can tell that I'm not in good health.
قال إنه يستطيع أن يقول أنني لست بصحة جيدة.
I need to take care of myself.
أحتاج أن أعتني بنفسي.
I received many prescriptions in a short while...
تلقيت العديد من الوصفات الطبية في فترة وجيزة ...
like female ginseng, white peony root...
مثل الجينسنغ الأنثوي وجذر الفاوانيا الأبيض ...
What else?
ماذا بعد؟
Anyway, there are so many that I can't remember.
على أي حال ، هناك الكثير الذي لا يمكنني تذكره.
He said I need to replenish my blood...
قال إنني بحاجة إلى تجديد دمي ...
and regulate my menstruation.
وتنظيم الدورة الشهرية.
Chinese medicine is broad and profound.
الطب الصيني واسع وعميق.
Why don't you listen to what he says?
لماذا لا تستمع لما يقول؟
Get a prescription.
احصل على وصفة طبية.
I have been here all morning.
لقد كنت هنا طوال الصباح.
I wonder if I'm the one treating him...
أتساءل عما إذا كنت أنا من أعامله ...
or if he's here to treat me.
أو إذا كان هنا ليعالجني.
Come back to me when you have the results.
عد إلي عندما تحصل على النتائج.
Okay, thank you.
حسنا شكرا لك.
Doctor.
طبيب.
The results are out.
النتائج خارج.
According to the colonoscopy,
حسب تنظير القولون
I think it's an early colon tumor.
أعتقد أنه ورم قولون مبكر.
But don't worry.
لكن لا تقلق.
If it's an early colon tumor...
إذا كان ورم القولون مبكرًا ...
and no metastasis has occurred,
ولم يحدث ورم خبيث ،
the sooner we find it, the sooner we can cure it.
كلما وجدناها في وقت مبكر ، كلما تمكنا من علاجها.
There's a very high chance that we can cure it.
هناك فرصة كبيرة للغاية لنتمكن من علاجها.
Doctor, what's the treatment?
دكتور ، ما هو العلاج؟
Do I need surgery?
هل أحتاج لعملية جراحية؟
It's a minimally invasive surgery.
إنها جراحة طفيفة التوغل.
At that time, our proctologists...
في ذلك الوقت ، أخصائيو أمراض المستقيم لدينا ...
will be responsible for your surgery.
سيكون مسؤولاً عن الجراحة الخاصة بك.
Okay.
تمام.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Look.
نظرة.
It's so cold now.
الجو بارد جدا الآن.
I shouldn't have brought you to Shanghai to travel at this time.
لم يكن يجب أن أحضرك إلى شنغهاي للسفر في هذا الوقت.
What are you saying?
ماذا تقول؟
I catch a cold easily in winter.
أصاب بالبرد بسهولة في الشتاء.
It doesn't matter where I am.
لا يهم أين أنا.
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
This is the first time we traveled together...
هذه هي المرة الأولى التي سافرنا فيها معًا ...
and you went straight to the emergency room.
وذهبت مباشرة إلى غرفة الطوارئ.
It's all my fault.
هذا كله خطأي.
I didn't think it through.
لم أفكر في الأمر.
It's just a mild fever.
إنها مجرد حمى خفيفة.
It's 38 degrees Celsius.
إنها 38 درجة مئوية.
How is that a mild fever?
كيف تكون هذه حمى خفيفة؟
Number 17, Chen Yan Ke.
رقم 17 ، تشين يان كي.
Please come to the first treatment room.
من فضلك تعال إلى غرفة العلاج الأولى.
It's our turn. Let's go.
حان دورنا.  لنذهب.
First treatment room.
غرفة العلاج الأولى.
Doctor.
طبيب.
She hasn't eaten all day.
لم تأكل طوال اليوم.
Even drinking water hurts.
حتى شرب الماء يؤلم.
Inflammation of the throat, tonsils abscess,
التهاب الحلق وخراج اللوزتين.
and some yellow exudates.
وبعض الإفرازات الصفراء.
Exudates?
النضح؟
It means pus. I think it's an infection.
يعني القيح.  أعتقد أنها عدوى.
Isn't it just a common cold? Why is there pus?
أليست مجرد نزلة برد؟  لماذا يوجد صديد؟
It's a common symptom of infection.
إنه عرض شائع للعدوى.
Don't worry too much.
لا تقلق كثيرا.
Let me check your lymph nodes again.
اسمحوا لي أن أتحقق من العقد الليمفاوية مرة أخرى.
Your lymph nodes are swollen.
العقد الليمفاوية متورمة.
How about this?
وماذا عن هذا؟
Let's go for a routine blood test and blood biochemistry test first.
دعنا نذهب لفحص الدم الروتيني واختبار الكيمياء الحيوية للدم أولاً.
Okay.
تمام.
Okay. Go ahead.
تمام.  إنطلق.
- Okay. - Thank you, doctor.
- تمام.  - شكرا لك دكتور.
Thank you, doctor.
شكرا لك دكتور.
Your dad...
والدك ...
thought I couldn't take care of you.
اعتقدت أنني لا أستطيع الاعتناء بك.
He doesn't want us to be together.
لا يريدنا أن نكون معًا.
I wasn't convinced at the time.
لم أكن مقتنعة في ذلك الوقت.
Now that I think about it,
الآن أن أفكر في ذلك،
your dad was right.
كان والدك على حق.
You lost all your confidence because of my dad.
لقد فقدت كل ثقتك بسبب والدي.
In my dad's eyes,
في عيون والدي ،
I'm too good for anyone.
أنا جيد جدًا لأي شخص.
Not even a celebrity.
ولا حتى من المشاهير.
Doctor.
طبيب.
The results are out.
النتائج خارج.
Please take a look at the results.
يرجى إلقاء نظرة على النتائج.
Elevated C-reactive protein and white blood cells in the blood.
ارتفاع البروتين التفاعلي C وخلايا الدم البيضاء في الدم.
I think it's a bacterial infection.
أعتقد أنها عدوى بكتيرية.
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
Da Zhi, let the doctor finish.
دا زي ، دع الطبيب ينتهي.
The more common bacteria...
البكتيريا الأكثر شيوعًا ...
that causes purulent tonsillitis...
الذي يسبب التهاب اللوزتين صديدي ...
is Streptococcus.
هي العقدية.
I'm prescribing you cephalosporins.
أنا أصف لك السيفالوسبورينات.
Take it orally for three days straight.
خذها شفويا لمدة ثلاثة أيام متتالية.
It'll basically heal completely.
سوف يشفى تمامًا.
Does that mean I'm fine?
هل هذا يعني أنني بخير؟
Yes, you're fine.
نعم انت بخير.
When you get home, get some rest and stay warm.
عندما تصل إلى المنزل ، احصل على قسط من الراحة وابقَ دافئًا.
Drink more water.
شرب المزيد من الماء.
Also, take your medicine on time to avoid reinfections.
أيضًا ، خذ دوائك في الوقت المحدد لتجنب الإصابة مرة أخرى.
Let's just stay in the hotel these few days.
دعنا نبقى في الفندق هذه الأيام القليلة.
This is my first time in Shanghai.
هذه هي المرة الأولى لي في شنغهاي.
It's fine. Let's play again when you feel better.
لا بأس.  لنلعب مرة أخرى عندما تشعر بتحسن.
All right. Go get the medicine.
حسنا.  اذهب واحضر الدواء.
- Okay. Thank you, doctor. - Thank you, doctor.
- تمام.  شكرا لك دكتور.  - شكرا لك دكتور.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
I'm fine. My feet hurt from walking too much.
أنا بخير.  قدمي تؤلمني من المشي كثيرًا.
Let's go back to the doctor.
دعنا نعود إلى الطبيب.
Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
Let's go back to the hotel and rest.
دعنا نعود إلى الفندق ونرتاح.
I've been so tired these past two days.
لقد كنت متعبًا جدًا في اليومين الماضيين.
All right.
حسنا.
Slowly.
ببطء.
Slow down.
ابطئ.
Let's go and eat.
لنذهب ونأكل.
I'm not eating. You go ahead.
أنا لا يأكل.  تفضل.
- Are you okay? - What's wrong?
- هل انت بخير؟  - ما هو الخطأ؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
There's a scratch.
هناك خدش.
It's fine.
لا بأس.
- Let's go. - Be careful.
- لنذهب.  - كن حذرا.
Why did you sprain your ankle?
لماذا التواء كاحلك؟
The shoes don't fit.
الأحذية لا تناسب.
Here.
هنا.
I'll apply some medicine for you.
سأقوم بتطبيق بعض الأدوية من أجلك.
Dr. Bai.
دكتور.  باي.
I can do it myself.
أستطيع أن أفعل ذلك بنفسي.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
- You're welcome. - Thank you.
- على الرحب والسعة.  - شكرًا لك.
Dr. Xiao.
دكتور شياو.
How big is your foot?
ما هو حجم قدمك؟
I think it's size 36 or 37.
أعتقد أنه مقاس 36 أو 37.
I bought these shoes online. I didn't try them on.
اشتريت هذه الأحذية عبر الإنترنت.  لم أجربهم.
That's the same as mine.
هذا هو نفسه لي.
I have a spare pair of shoes.
لدي زوج احتياطي من الأحذية.
I'll get them for you.
سأحضرهم لك.
Wait.
انتظر.
I'll go with you.
سأذهب معك.
No, I...
لا ، أنا ...
Let me help you.
دعني اساعدك.
Slowly.
ببطء.
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
Lin Zhi.
لين تشي.
There was a female patient in the morning...
كان هناك مريضة في الصباح ...
with a tonsils infection who came to Shanghai to travel.
مصابًا بعدوى في اللوزتين جاءوا إلى شنغهاي للسفر.
Check the records.
تحقق من السجلات.
Contact her.
تواصل معها.
Tell her to come back for a follow-up.
قل لها أن تعود للمتابعة.
Okay.
تمام.
These shoes are quite comfortable. Where did you buy them?
هذه الأحذية مريحة للغاية.  من أين لك شرائها؟
Online.
متصل.
It's a lot cheaper than shopping malls.
إنها أرخص بكثير من مراكز التسوق.
Dr. Xiao.
دكتور شياو.
Can't you tell Bai Zhu likes you?
ألا يمكنك إخبار باي تشو معجب بك؟
Dr. Bai and I are colleagues.
الدكتور باي وأنا زملاء.
I'm not blind.
أنا لست أعمى.
I can tell.
استطيع أن أقول.
Bai Zhu treats you differently.
يعاملك باي تشو بشكل مختلف.
You treat him differently too.
أنت تعامله بشكل مختلف أيضًا.
I'll get mad if you say that again.
سأغضب إذا قلت ذلك مرة أخرى.
Then I'll say one last thing.
ثم سأقول شيئًا أخيرًا.
He doesn't deserve you.
لا يستحقك.
That's all.
هذا كل شئ.
Thank you, doctor.
شكرا لك دكتور.
What are you doing sneaking around?
ماذا تفعل تتسلل؟
Does it have anything to do with you?
هل له علاقة بك؟
Come in.
ادخل.
Dr. Bai.
دكتور.  باي.
The patient with a tonsils infection is here.
المريض المصاب بالتهاب اللوزتين موجود هنا.
Okay.
تمام.
Chen Zhi, let's go.
تشين تشى ، دعنا نذهب.
Do you need two doctors for tonsils infection?
هل تحتاج طبيبين لعدوى اللوزتين؟
You don't understand.
أنت لا تفهم.
Dr. Bai is going to train Chen Zhi.
سيقوم الدكتور باي بتدريب Chen Zhi.
The doctor asked us to come back in such a hurry.
طلب منا الطبيب العودة بسرعة.
Could something have happened?
هل يمكن أن يحدث شيء ما؟
Don't jinx me. Touch wood.
لا نحس لي.  إلمس الخشب.
Touch wood.
إلمس الخشب.
Did you hurt your leg?
هل جرحت رجلك؟
The back of my heels are scraped.
تم كشط الجزء الخلفي من كعبي.
Take off your shoes so I can see.
اخلع حذائك حتى أتمكن من الرؤية.
- Lie down on the bed. - Your feet.
- الاستلقاء على السرير.  - قدمك.
I'm going to tear off the Band-Aid.
سأقوم بتمزيق الإسعافات الأولية.
Is it that serious?
هل هذا جاد؟
Your swelling is serious.
انتفاخك خطير.
You'll need surgery to drain it.
ستحتاج لعملية جراحية لتصريفها.
Lin Zhi, get ready.
لين تشي ، استعد.
Okay.
تمام.
Let me tell you.
دعني أخبرك.
Later, we have to remove some pus for bacteria culture.
في وقت لاحق ، يتعين علينا إزالة بعض القيح من أجل ثقافة البكتيريا.
Bacteria culture?
ثقافة البكتيريا؟
What kind of illness is this?
أي نوع من المرض هذا؟
Only after the bacteria culture results come out...
فقط بعد ظهور نتائج ثقافة البكتيريا ...
can we deal with the illness.
هل يمكننا التعامل مع المرض.
Okay.
تمام.
Why is it so swollen?
لماذا هو منتفخ جدا؟
I didn't notice it.
لم ألاحظ ذلك.
It's all my fault.
هذا كله خطأي.
Why didn't I notice it sooner?
لماذا لم ألاحظ ذلك عاجلاً؟
Okay, here we go.
حسنًا ، ها نحن ذا.
It's going to hurt a little. Bear with it.
سوف يؤلم قليلا.  تحمل ذلك.
It'll be over soon.
سوف ينتهي قريبا.
Bear with it.
تحمل ذلك.
Is it the same kind of pus in her throat?
هل هو نفس نوع القيح في حلقها؟
We don't know yet.
لا نعرف بعد.
We have to cultivate the bacteria to know.
علينا أن نزرع البكتيريا لنعرف.
It won't take long.
لن يستغرق الأمر وقتًا طويلاً.
Dr. Bai.
دكتور.  باي.
Is the infection in her throat and ankle...
هي عدوى في حلقها وكاحلها ...
really the same bacteria?
حقا نفس البكتيريا؟
Are you serious?
هل أنت جاد؟
I've never seen anything like this.
لم أرَ شيئًا كهذا من قبل.
I wonder how you graduated.
أتساءل كيف تخرجت.
Bacteria will spread everywhere once it enters our blood.
ستنتشر البكتيريا في كل مكان بمجرد دخولها إلى دمائنا.
I know that.
وأنا أعلم ذلك.
What I mean is...
ما أعنيه هو...
if it's bacteria,
إذا كانت البكتيريا ،
can it spread this fast in such a short time?
وهل ينتشر هذا الصيام في مثل هذا الوقت القصير؟
You've finally asked a meaningful question.
لقد سألت أخيرًا سؤالًا ذا مغزى.
Let's wait for the result.
دعنا ننتظر النتيجة.
Don't give up.
لا تستسلم.
Dr. Xu said Dr. Bai is trying to train you.
قال الدكتور شو أن الدكتور باي يحاول تدريبك.
That's how I consoled myself.
هكذا عزيت نفسي.
- All right. Go get your medicine. - Okay. Thank you.
- حسنا.  اذهب واحضر دوائك.  - تمام.  شكرًا لك.
Dr. Bai.
دكتور.  باي.
Chen Yan Ke's test results came out.
جاءت نتائج اختبار Chen Yan Ke.
Please take a look.
من فضلك الق نظرة.
Klebsiella pneumoniae.
الكلبسيلة الرئوية.
It's a superbug.
إنها حشرة خارقة.
This Klebsiella pneumoniae can usually be found in hospitals.
يمكن العثور على هذا الكلبسيلة الرئوية عادة في المستشفيات.
It's rarely exposed to ordinary people in everyday life.
نادرًا ما يتعرض للناس العاديين في الحياة اليومية.
Is she infected in our hospital?
هل هي مصابة في مستشفانا؟
It won't happen so soon.
لن يحدث ذلك قريبًا.
Dr. Bai, I remember now.
دكتور باي ، أتذكر الآن.
When I changed her dressing just now,
عندما غيرت ملابسها الآن ،
I heard them say...
سمعتهم يقولون ...
that the patient's boyfriend was hospitalized for two weeks...
أن صديق المريض دخل المستشفى لمدة أسبوعين ...
due to pneumonia six months ago.
بسبب الالتهاب الرئوي منذ ستة أشهر.
Do you think he was carrying it then?
هل تعتقد أنه كان يحملها حينها؟
A healthy carrier.
حامل صحي.
They're a couple.
إنهما زوجان.
It's highly contagious.
إنه شديد العدوى.
Listen.
استمع.
You give the patient a piperacillin injection first.
يتم إعطاء المريض حقنة بيبيراسيلين أولاً.
Then get a sample from the boyfriend and get it tested.
ثم الحصول على عينة من صديقها واختبارها.
Okay.
تمام.
If something like this happens next time,
إذا حدث شيء كهذا في المرة القادمة ،
you'll do it.
ستفعلها.
Me?
أنا؟
Thank you, Dr. Bai.
شكرا لك دكتور باي.
I got the illness from Da Zhi?
حصلت على المرض من دا تشي؟
- Yes. - That's impossible.
- نعم.  - هذا مستحيل.
I don't have any symptoms.
ليس لدي أي أعراض.
You don't have any symptoms now,
ليس لديك أي أعراض الآن ،
but you had pneumonia once six months ago.
لكنك أصبت بالتهاب رئوي مرة واحدة قبل ستة أشهر.
At that time, you got infected with Klebsiella pneumoniae.
في ذلك الوقت ، أصبت بـ Klebsiella pneumoniae.
That's why you've been carrying the bacteria.
لهذا السبب كنت تحمل البكتيريا.
That's how Chen Yan Ke got infected.
هذه هي الطريقة التي أصيب بها تشين يان كي.
But in the past, both of you never got sick.
لكن في الماضي ، لم يمرض كلاكما أبدًا.
This time, it's because you came to travel...
هذه المرة ، لأنك أتيت للسفر ...
and she was overworked.
وكانت مرهقة.
Her body was too weak, so she got sick.
كان جسدها ضعيفًا جدًا ، لذا مرضت.
I carried it with me?
حملتها معي؟
We found this bacteria in your throat and nasal cavity.
وجدنا هذه البكتيريا في الحلق والأنف.
But I come into contact with so many people...
لكنني على اتصال بالعديد من الناس ...
at work every day...
في العمل كل يوم ...
and I've never seen anyone get such an illness.
ولم أر أي شخص يصاب بمثل هذا المرض من قبل.
This bacteria...
هذه البكتيريا ...
can only be transmitted through contact with body fluids.
لا يمكن أن ينتقل إلا من خلال ملامسة سوائل الجسم.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I...
أنا...
I didn't know I had this bacteria with me.
لم أكن أعلم أن لدي هذه البكتيريا معي.
It's not your fault.
انها ليست غلطتك.
You said it yourself.
قلت ذلك بنفسك.
You didn't know that.
أنت لا تعرف ذلك.
Moreover, I feel much better now.
علاوة على ذلك ، أشعر بتحسن كبير الآن.
Did the medicine you injected me work?
هل الدواء الذي حقنتني به يعمل؟
- Yes. - Why don't you give Da Zhi...
- نعم.  - لماذا لا تعطي دا تشي ...
the same medicine as me?
نفس الدواء مثلي؟
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
Get rid of all the bacteria in my body.
تخلص من كل البكتيريا الموجودة في جسدي.
Even if I give you an injection, it won't be able to do much.
حتى لو أعطيتك حقنة ، فلن تكون قادرة على فعل الكثير.
Why?
لماذا ا؟
Because you've been carrying this bacteria for over six months.
لأنك تحمل هذه البكتيريا منذ أكثر من ستة أشهر.
The bacteria are all over your body.
البكتيريا منتشرة في جميع أنحاء جسمك.
Antibiotics won't help you much.
لن تساعدك المضادات الحيوية كثيرًا.
Wait. What does that mean?
انتظر.  ماذا يعني ذلك؟
Do I have to carry the bacteria for the rest of my life?
هل يجب علي حمل البكتيريا لبقية حياتي؟
If you don't have an attack, I don't think it'll affect you much.
إذا لم تتعرض لهجوم ، فلا أعتقد أنه سيؤثر عليك كثيرًا.
If I carry it all the time,
إذا كنت أحملها طوال الوقت ،
won't it still infect Xiao Ke in the future?
ألن تستمر في إصابة شياو كي في المستقبل؟
It's possible.
انه ممكن.
Paying attention to precautions during physical contact...
الاهتمام بالاحتياطات أثناء الاتصال الجسدي ...
can reduce the risk of infection.
يمكن أن تقلل من خطر الإصابة.
We'll make it work.
سنجعلها تعمل.
There will be a way.
سيكون هناك طريق.
Isn't that right, doctor?
أليس هذا صحيح يا دكتور؟
If we find a more effective antibiotic,
إذا وجدنا مضادًا حيويًا أكثر فعالية ،
I'll let you know.
سأخبرك.
Take care of yourself.
اعتنِ بنفسك.
Come to us if you have any questions.
تعال إلينا إذا كان لديك أي أسئلة.
Let's go.
لنذهب.
Your dad was right.
كان والدك على حق.
I should've taken better care of you.
كان يجب أن أعتني بك بشكل أفضل.
I even spread the illness to you.
حتى أنني قمت بنشر المرض لك.
Da Zhi.
دا تشي.
All right.
حسنا.
If there's the latest treatment method,
إذا كان هناك أحدث طريقة علاج ،
please tell me.
أرجوك قل لي.
Okay, thank you.
حسنا شكرا لك.
You came at the right time.
أتيت في الوقت المناسب.
This is some information about the prevention of Klebsiella.
هذه بعض المعلومات حول الوقاية من الكلبسيلا.
You can read it at home.
يمكنك قراءتها في المنزل.
No.
رقم.
There's no need for prevention.
ليست هناك حاجة للوقاية.
Please...
لو سمحت...
give this letter...
أعط هذه الرسالة ...
to Xiao Ke.
إلى Xiao Ke.
I don't have the courage to tell her myself.
ليس لدي الشجاعة لأخبرها بنفسي.
I can't take care of Xiao Ke.
لا يمكنني الاعتناء بشياو كي.
Please.
لو سمحت.
Dr. Bai, what should we do?
دكتور باي ، ماذا علينا أن نفعل؟
Throw the letter away.
ارمي الخطاب بعيدا.
Don't you hear me? Throw the letter away.
لا تسمعني  ارمي الخطاب بعيدا.
Go and find Chen Yan Ke right now.
اذهب وابحث عن Chen Yan Ke الآن.
Take her to the entrance and stop him.
خذها إلى المدخل وأوقفه.
Da Zhi.
دا تشي.
Are you just going to run away so sneakily?
هل ستهرب فقط بشكل متستر؟
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
You abandon me because of such a trivial matter.
أنت تتخلى عني بسبب هذه المسألة التافهة.
I carry bacteria with me all the time.
أحمل البكتيريا معي طوال الوقت.
I can infect you at any time.
يمكنني أن أصبك في أي وقت.
Sir.
سيد.
I don't think you need to carry this burden.
لا أعتقد أنك بحاجة لتحمل هذا العبء.
It's too heavy for you.
انها ثقيلة جدا بالنسبة لك.
You didn't know about this.
أنت لا تعرف عن هذا.
You just need to protect yourselves from now on.
ما عليك سوى حماية أنفسكم من الآن فصاعدًا.
There's still a chance of infection.
لا تزال هناك فرصة للإصابة بالعدوى.
As a doctor,
كطبيب،
I deal with all kinds of incurable diseases every day.
أتعامل مع جميع أنواع الأمراض المستعصية كل يوم.
I've also seen separations between loved ones.
لقد رأيت أيضًا تباعدًا بين الأحباء.
It's rare to see someone...
من النادر رؤية شخص ما ...
who gives up love so easily like you.
من يتخلى عن الحب مثلك بسهولة.
I don't know...
لا أعلم...
if you have heard of Lin Ruo Yun...
إذا كنت قد سمعت عن Lin Ruo Yun ...
and Mr. Li Shi Lei in our hospital before.
والسيد لي شي لي في مستشفانا من قبل.
The struggle Ms. Lin faced is much more painful than yours.
النضال الذي واجهته السيدة لين هو أكثر إيلامًا من كفاحك.
And it's also about...
وهو أيضًا عن ...
the life and death of the person she loves.
حياة وموت الشخص الذي تحبه.
Even though Ms. Lin chose to let go in the end,
على الرغم من أن السيدة لين اختارت التخلي في النهاية ،
it's about respecting the will of the one she loves.
يتعلق الأمر باحترام إرادة من تحب.
Love is between two people.
الحب بين شخصين.
Before you make a decision,
قبل اتخاذ قرار ،
have you asked your lover?
هل سألت حبيبك
Before this, we had an elderly couple here.
قبل ذلك ، كان لدينا زوجان عجوزان هنا.
The woman had a car accident and was in a vegetative state.
تعرضت المرأة لحادث سيارة وكانت في حالة إنبات.
From a medical point of view,
من وجهة نظر طبية ،
even if we continue with the treatment,
حتى لو واصلنا العلاج ،
I don't think she'll wake up.
لا أعتقد أنها ستستيقظ.
But her lover didn't give up on her.
لكن حبيبها لم يتخل عنها.
He read his diary to her every day...
كان يقرأ لها مذكراته كل يوم ...
to help her recall the bits and pieces...
لمساعدتها على تذكر الأجزاء والقطع ...
that both of them have experienced
التي عاشها كلاهما
He believes that she'll wake up one day...
يعتقد أنها ستستيقظ ذات يوم ...
and another miracle will happen.
وستحدث معجزة أخرى.
In fact,
في الواقع،
you're already very blessed to live in this peaceful age.
أنت بالفعل محظوظ جدًا للعيش في هذا العصر الذي يسوده السلام.
If you get sick,
إذا مرضت ،
there are such good doctors...
هناك أطباء جيدون ...
and such advanced equipment...
وهذه المعدات المتطورة ...
that can treat you.
يمكن أن يعاملك.
Do you know?
هل تعرف؟
There are a lot of places in the world...
هناك الكثير من الأماكن في العالم ...
where war is still raging.
حيث لا تزال الحرب مستعرة.
If the people there are injured or sick,
إذا كان الناس هناك مصابين أو مرضى ،
they may be gone just like that.
ربما ذهبوا هكذا.
It's not easy for two people who love each other...
الأمر ليس سهلاً على شخصين يحبان بعضهما البعض ...
to be together.
لنكون معا.
How can you be defeated by a tiny bacteria?
كيف يمكن أن تهزم بكتيريا صغيرة؟
Don't people who love each other...
لا يحب الناس بعضهم البعض ...
have to overcome all kinds of difficulties together?
يجب أن يتغلبوا على جميع أنواع الصعوبات معًا؟
Thank you, doctor.
شكرا لك دكتور.
You're right.
أنت على حق.
I won't run away.
لن أهرب.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Xiao Ke.
شياو كه.
Dr. Bai.
دكتور.  باي.
What happened?
ماذا حدث؟
It's nothing.
إنه لاشيء.
Dr. Bai.
دكتور.  باي.
How did you know that the letter wouldn't work?
كيف عرفت أن الرسالة لن تعمل؟
The couple made up.
اختلق الزوجان.
If you want to be a good doctor,
إذا كنت تريد أن تكون طبيبة جيدة ،
you don't just see diseases...
أنت لا ترى الأمراض فقط ...
but also people.
ولكن أيضا الناس.
Didn't see the way that girl looked at that young man?
ألم ترَ كيف نظرت تلك الفتاة إلى ذلك الشاب؟
Would she stop loving him because of Klebsiella pneumoniae?
هل ستتوقف عن حبه بسبب الكلبسيلا الرئوية؟